<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin Zimmerman</title>
    <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Justin Zimmerman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Justin Zimmerman.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 09:26:55 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://justinzimmerman.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 09:26:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Justin Zimmerman. I work at Red Ventures as a Full Stack Software Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bestrida</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/bestrida/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 09:45:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/bestrida/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I recently published &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/lBRCeb.i&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/a&gt; to the iOS app store for my submission to the 2016 Strava Developer Challenge. Here is a brief overview of the application. Strava.com is a popular and widely used website and mobile app that over one million cyclists and runners use to track their activity via GPS. Whenever you go for a run or ride your bike, Strava will track and store your activity and provide you with useful statistics. As awesome as it is, a major thing Strava does not offer is a way to challenge your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bestrida&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bestrida, swedish translation &amp;ldquo;to challenge&amp;rdquo;, is a Strava.com segment based application that allows you to challenge your friends to running and cycling segments. With the chaotic schedules many of us have, it’s hard to carve out time to actually meet up with a friend and go for a run or ride. Your friends no longer have an excuse to keep dodging your challenges just because you&amp;rsquo;re an Ironman and they’re a weekend warrior. You can challenge your friends using the app, anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenge-feed&#34;&gt;Challenge Feed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After logging in, the user is presented with the Challenge Feed. The Challenge Feed aggregates all of the challenges that the user has received from other users and challenges that the user has sent out to their friends. The user can click on a particular challenge and preview the segment for that challenge. Here we can see the relevant metrics for this segment. The user can also have the option to cancel the challenge. Users can accept or decline challenges from the feed as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-challenge&#34;&gt;Create Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the screen, the user can click on the “Create Challenge” button to create a new challenge. To create a challenge, the user will first select a challenger. They have the option to either select from a list of their 3 most frequently challenged friends or search from the list of their Strava friends to challenge. The user will then select a segment. Similar to selecting a challenger, the user will have the option to either select from a list of their 3 most frequently completed segments or search for starred or recently completed segments. The last step is to select a completion date which acts like an expiration date by which both users must complete that particular challenge. Once the challenge has been created and accepted by the other user, it will be displayed on the “Active Challenges” tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;active-challenges&#34;&gt;Active Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the “Active Challenges” tab, the user can view a list of all active challenges, which are challenges that have been accepted
by both parties. The Active Challenge feed shows the opponent, the segment, and the completion date. You can click on the
active challenge to view more detailed information about that particular challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the user completes an activity on Strava that covers the segment, the user can click in to the Active Challenge Detail view to complete the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;completed-challenges&#34;&gt;Completed Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the challenge is completed, the user can view the Completed Challenge feed to see whether they have won, lost, or are waiting for their opponent to complete the challenge. When the challenge is completed by both parties, you can see whether you won or lost, the segment name, the distance and specific details about the user and their opponent including completion time, heart rate, cadence, and wattage during the segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This application was built with React Native, and Node, with a Mongo database to store users, segments, and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Download &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/lBRCeb.i&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/a&gt; today to start challenging your friends and improving your workouts and segment times!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching From Bash to ZSH</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/switching-from-bash-to-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:29:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/switching-from-bash-to-zsh/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I recently switched from BASH (Bourne Again SHell) to ZSH after hearing about z shell&amp;rsquo;s many benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main benefits for me were better autocompletion, and file globbing, and better autocorrection. I spent quite a few weekends doing research on whether to switch or not, and finally I bit the bullet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-zsh-with-homebrew&#34;&gt;Installing ZSH with Homebrew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly straightforward to do. The default version of ZSH shipped with OSX is 5.0.2. The latest version of ZSH at the time of writing is 5.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-zsh&#34;&gt;Download ZSH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew update
brew install zsh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installation is completed, we need to insert the location into &lt;code&gt;/etc/shells&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; sudo vim /etc/shells
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insert the following line to the end of the file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/zsh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the file path that homebrew system linked ZSH to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set the default shell to ZSH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chsh -s /usr/local/bin/zsh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might require a restart, but once completed verify zsh is your default shell by running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo $SHELL
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have the latest ZSH running as default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-oh-my-zsh&#34;&gt;Installing oh-my-zsh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&#34;&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/a&gt; repository is a very large open source collection of zsh plugins and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/wiki/themes&#34;&gt;themes&lt;/a&gt;. While there are a few alternatives to oh-my-zsh, such as prezto. I wanted to be able get started right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install oh-my-zsh run the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sh -c &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/master/tools/install.sh)&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will modify your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes with the &amp;ldquo;robbyrussell&amp;rdquo; theme as default, but I wanted something a bit more exciting like the &amp;ldquo;agnoster&amp;rdquo; theme as pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/img/agnoster.png&#34; alt=&#34;agnoster theme&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To switch themes, open your .zshrc file and replace this line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ZSH_THEME=&amp;quot;robbyrussell&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ZSH_THEME=&amp;quot;agnoster&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a great time to copy over your custom &lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; configs to the &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-powerline-fonts&#34;&gt;Installing Powerline Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem is that the agnoster theme requires &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/powerline/fonts&#34;&gt;Powerline fonts&lt;/a&gt; to show the &amp;ldquo;pipeline&amp;rdquo; icons. Fortunately installing the fonts is very simple and comes with a script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, clone down the &lt;code&gt;powerline/fonts&lt;/code&gt; repository into your github work folder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/powerline/fonts.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;code&gt;cd fonts&lt;/code&gt; into the fonts repository and run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./install.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once completed, this also might require a restart to show the new fonts available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your terminal (iTerm2 or HyperTerm) change the default font to one of the &amp;ldquo;for powerline&amp;rdquo; fonts. I chose &lt;code&gt;Meslo for Powerline&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once selected, you have successfully completed setting up ZSH with oh-my-zsh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on your awesome new terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching from iTerm to HyperTerm</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/switching-from-iterm-to-hyperterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 22:26:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/switching-from-iterm-to-hyperterm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://zeit.co/&#34;&gt;zeit.co&lt;/a&gt; released to the world a wonderful terminal built with JavaScript / HTML / CSS called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperterm.org/&#34;&gt;HyperTerm&lt;/a&gt;. Even better yet, this terminal is fully customizable with open source plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not one to change my development environment constantly, but this electron app was simple to install on OSX and even easier to customize programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope is to demo how simple it is to get started with HyperTerm, and show how I only added a few lines to the configuration file to have a terminal I enjoy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-hyperterm&#34;&gt;Installing HyperTerm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install HyperTerm on OSX simply install the .pkg file from their &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperterm.org/#installation&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, use your editor of choice to open &lt;code&gt;~/.hyperterm.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the default configuration is very good, I have a few recommended configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuring-hyperterm&#34;&gt;Configuring HyperTerm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, change the theme by simply adding &lt;code&gt;hyperterm-solarized-dark&lt;/code&gt; to the plugins array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugins: [
    &#39;hyperterm-solarized-dark&#39;,
  ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save the configuration, and HyperTerm will automatically update for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also enjoy using the &lt;code&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/code&gt; plugin to open links with your browser, we can also add this to the plugins array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugins: [
    &#39;hyperterm-solarized-dark&#39;,
    &#39;hyperlinks&#39;
  ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I use ZSH with a Powerline font, I can simply update the fonts to include &lt;code&gt;Meslo for Powerline&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// font family with optional fallbacks
fontFamily: &#39;&amp;quot;Meslo LG L DZ for Powerline&amp;quot;, Menlo, &amp;quot;DejaVu Sans Mono&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Lucida Console&amp;quot;, monospace&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also modify the default window size of HyperTerm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// size of window by pixels (width, height)
windowSize: [1300, 650]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a few lines of code, we now have a fully customizable terminal!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 12</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 22:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The realization that Week 12 has finally come to an end is definitely bitter-sweet. I have spent over 11 hours a day for the past 12 weeks learning Full-Stack Software Engineering. While I am looking forward getting back to a regular sleep schedule, I have learned more than I could imagine, and met many amazing people along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 12 consisted of finalizing resumes, creating cover letters, and preparing for the job search ahead. This was one of the most interesting weeks of Hack Reactor, although I can&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail on their job search process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have greatly enjoyed the Hack Reactor journey, and I hope if you are considering Hack Reactor that you have found my 12 weeks of blog posts insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 11</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 08:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With our product, Bestrida, to MVP (Minimum Viable Product) we will continue to improve our MVP features, as well as the look and feel of product, for the remainder of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our product finally received a much needed design overhaul, and we are definitely happy with the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/img/bestrida.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bestrida&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stretch-goals&#34;&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above image, we are able to pull from the Strava API segment effort data for the user to view additional metrics on how well they performed during their effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thesis-presentations&#34;&gt;Final Thesis Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to boil down three weeks of work into a simple 3 minute presentation, but fortunately I was paired with not only incredible developers, but excellent communicators. You can find our presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sw_mcAhgQo4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one more week until class is over! Onward to hiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 10</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 19:05:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-10/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With Thesis moving along very nicely, here is what happened in week 10!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;authentication&#34;&gt;Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges faced this week during thesis is removing API keys from the client side. With a mobile application, you should consider all of your code accessible for the world to see. This would allow for any user to view your API&amp;rsquo;s secret key allowing other user&amp;rsquo;s to make (potentially) malicious requests to the API. This should of course, be avoided at all costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reimplemented the authentication to be completely server side. To do this, we used passport.js and JSON Web Tokens. The client will send the JWT to the server on each request. Once sent, the server will then intercept the request, making sure the user has a valid token and that the token hasn&amp;rsquo;t expired yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a great learning experience for the entire team, and one that certainly helped us better understand token-based authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bestrida&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have finally made it to MVP! The server creates challenges, the user can view and accept these challenges, and we can finally declare a winner based off live Strava data. This has been a very challenging but rewarding process for the entire team, and we are so excited to show off our product to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With next week being a solo week for Christmas vacation, I will post again in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Whiteboarding: Triggers</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/on-whiteboarding-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 10:37:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/on-whiteboarding-triggers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I will be the first to admit, I struggle in whiteboarding situations, especially in the context of technical interviewing when triggers arise. I hope this post helps you become better at whiteboarding when these certain triggers occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recognized that there are two types of triggers that happen while whiteboarding. The first trigger is an interpersonal trigger that I will call a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;spiraling&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; trigger. The next is an external trigger that I will call a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;questioning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what each of the triggers are and what we can do about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spiraling-triggers&#34;&gt;Spiraling Triggers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/T1qCytOwqL6A8.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Spiral&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first type of trigger is what happens when our plan starts to &amp;ldquo;spiral downward&amp;rdquo; and ultimately fall apart the moment when we realize our initial solution to the problem &lt;em&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started attempting technical questions, or what I like to call &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;toy problems&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, spiraling triggers were the demise of many solutions. So what can we do about them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is &lt;strong&gt;recognizing&lt;/strong&gt; that you have started to spiral downward. It seems like something obvious right? Maybe not at first to the unexperienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts of &amp;ldquo;Oh man, my solution doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I can&amp;rsquo;t solve this. What am I even doing here? I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I am wasting this interviewers time!&amp;rdquo; can easily start creeping into the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to recognize when the spiraling starts, and quickly break out of it. &lt;strong&gt;Take a deep breath, and stand up straight.&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously. It helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/3o85xGwYPfshlyYLCM.gif&#34; alt=&#34;sigh&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to get oxygen back into our brains and start thinking down the correct path again. Wasting brain power on how we aren&amp;rsquo;t solving the problem won&amp;rsquo;t help us find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry though, if we can recognize our spiraling, it becomes much easier to break out of the spiral after some practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking a breath, start thinking of what new information has been introduced. This segues nicely into the next trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;questioning-triggers&#34;&gt;Questioning Triggers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next type of trigger is a &lt;strong&gt;questioning trigger&lt;/strong&gt;. This occurs when new information is provided by the interviewer, or a new realization modifies our understanding of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an interviewer asks &amp;ldquo;Does that work?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Is that right?&amp;rdquo; consider it a questioning trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few steps when approached with a questioning trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####1. Amend the current line of pseudocode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe this isn&amp;rsquo;t as earth shattering as we might have hoped, but do not overlook this simple strategy. For me, when a &lt;em&gt;questioning trigger&lt;/em&gt; occurs, I think of a solution and want to rush to the beginning of my pseudocode and start changing everything from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/BfBqQV47hLFh6.gif&#34; alt=&#34;best idea&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually counter productive and will hamper our ability to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the big deal? By the time we get back to the current line of pseudocode, we&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten our epiphany making it harder for us to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####2. Visualize the conflicting information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say our toy problem requires us to traverse a tree and we find a flaw in our logic. Trees are excellent opportunities to visualize what our data looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, we realize our solution won&amp;rsquo;t traverse left nodes if right nodes of the tree have data in them. Let&amp;rsquo;s visualize examples of edge cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;USEFUL DIAGRAM!
      (N)
    /      \
  (Null)    (RC)
            /
          (LC2)

USEFUL DIAGRAM!
      (N)
    /      \
  (LC)    (Null)

USEFUL DIAGRAM!
      (N)
    /      \
  (Null)    (Null)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we can visualize different edge cases, it will be a lot easier to incorporate solutions into our pseudocode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####3. Create new example data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After visualizing the new information, our next step is to create example data to help solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we realize our problem needs a function that will require a callback to store data asynchronously, think of example data that we can provide to our solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  asyncMap([
   function(cb){
     setTimeout(function(){
       cb(&#39;one&#39;);
     }, 200);
   },
   function(cb){
     setTimeout(function(){
       cb(&#39;two&#39;);
    }, 100);
   }
  ],
   function(results){
     // the results array will equal [&#39;one&#39;,&#39;two&#39;] even though
     // the second function had a shorter timeout.
     console.log(results); // [&#39;one&#39;, &#39;two&#39;]
 });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write an example function, include an example timeout length, and example data that results from the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is imperative that our example data includes edge cases. The more edge cases we add to our example data, the easier finding a solution will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####4. Step through pseudocode with example data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical step that I am continuing to work on while solving toy problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to write in-line pseudocode as if we were the compiler. Using our example data created in the previous step, iterate through each line of the pseudocode. We want to write down what our variables store at each pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// after 100ms
// 2
// counter = 1
// result = [,,&#39;one&#39;]
// check if 1 === 2 -&amp;gt; false


// after 200ms
// 2
// counter = 2
// result = [,, &#39;two&#39;]
// check if 2 === 2 -&amp;gt; true
		// callback(result) Boom! // -&amp;gt; [&#39;one, &#39;two&#39;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us even greater insight to any flaws within our pseudocode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####5. Finish pseudocode completely before rushing to write code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I figure out part of the solution, I get excited and want to start coding right away. From experience, I can safely say this is the best way to run into additional problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to be sure to finish iterating through pseudocode with our example data from step 4. This allows us to get a better idea of what exactly needs to happen to solve the problem, and write correct code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to make our pseudocode a cheat sheet, not a general overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in whiteboarding situations, we only want to be doing 2 out of 3 tasks at all times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do more than 2 of these things at once, we are at risk of spiraling. This is why it is important that we have complete pseudocode before we start coding. We now only have to worry about the last 2 points: &lt;strong&gt;writing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;talking&lt;/strong&gt; when writing actual code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/mNpgNpZmflO3S.gif&#34; alt=&#34;everything&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read this lengthy post. If you can remember these steps I guarantee you will not only come to a solution, but impress your interviewer along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 9</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 09:50:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-09/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Week 9 is finished at Hack Reactor, and thesis projects are in full swing! While there aren&amp;rsquo;t many things on the schedule, thesis is all about trying to build the best product in the 3 short weeks you have dedicated to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thesis&#34;&gt;Thesis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, this is a perfect summary of life during thesis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/wJ4IcDJ.gif&#34; alt=&#34;thesis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have no fear, little buddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building a product can feel this way sometimes, I am having an awesome time learning and problem solving to create the best app we can possibly produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our thesis project, my group has decided to build upon Strava&amp;rsquo;s extensive API. We are seriously fortunate to have such a great API to leverage for our product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, here is a little bit about Bestrida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bestrida&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name pays homage to Strava by also leaning upon it Swedish vocabulary. Strava is swedish for &amp;ldquo;to strive&amp;rdquo;, while Bestrida is swedish for &amp;ldquo;to challenge&amp;rdquo;. Which is exactly what our app does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bestrida will allow a user to challenge anyone they follow to a particular segment. The user will pick a person to challenge, a segment, and a date the challenge will be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of my friends are great to ride with, but like most cyclists, they are also always up for a short sprint through a well known Strava segment. This application will take your casual ride with friends to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for this week. Next week I will continue to describe Bestrida, and discuss topics learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 0</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:19:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s finally that time! After completing the pre-course work, I start my journey with Hack Reactor today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to write on a weekly basis about the new topics covered, and what was focused on during my time here at Hack Reactor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the pre-course we focused on gaining a firm understanding of web development technologies such as HTML, CSS, and jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming concepts such as scope, execution contexts, objects, and recursion were discussed in great length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to start my journey into Software Engineering with Hack Reactor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Remote Prep Week 4</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 07:48:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like that, the four week course is at an end. I have really enjoyed the opportunity to learn such a large amount of material in such a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has definitely been a great learning experience for me. If you are considering going to Hack Reactor, then this course will really show you what you&amp;rsquo;re getting in to. Also, if you are wondering if you can learn in the Hack Reactor Remote online class, the answer is yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last week we learned the following concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ajax-json&#34;&gt;AJAX &amp;amp; JSON&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off the week learning how to use AJAX to interact with servers behind the scenes using JavaScript without having to reload the page. This was really fun, and very powerful. We leveraged the Open Weather Map API to load local temperature information to our sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;higher-order-functions&#34;&gt;Higher Order Functions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was probably the most important day of the entire class. As we worked through rewriting higher order functions like each, map, and filter, we had 1 on 1 interviews with the instructor to determine how we were doing. This was valuable feedback, and the instructor was very helpful in pointing to the next topics I should focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;object-oriented-javascript&#34;&gt;Object Oriented Javascript&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked in to more Object manipulation today, leveraging the object data type to structure our programs, rather than functions. We learned how to create our own methods in our own objects, and introduced decorator patterns and factory patterns code structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;model-view-controller&#34;&gt;Model View Controller&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We created a simple MVC using factory pattern objects to leverage the Imgur API and the SoundCloud API. This was a very rewarding project where I learned quite a bit of material using both simple and complex APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;portfolio-and-hiring&#34;&gt;Portfolio and Hiring&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day consisted of learning a variety of ways to improve your online presence. These included tips and tricks on how to improve your Github and LinkedIn. We discussed the importance of an online portfolio site, and blogging about technical concepts. We also covered the basics on resumes, cover letters, applying for jobs, and how to prepare for interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Remote Prep Week 3</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 07:43:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot believe we have already completed 3 weeks of class! I have learned a considerable amount along the way. Here are some of the topics that were covered this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;functions&#34;&gt;Functions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are getting into the good stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Functions&#34;&gt;Functions&lt;/a&gt; are one of the most critical tools for any good JavaScript programmer. We discussed creating functions, invoking functions, and storing functions as variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;events&#34;&gt;Events&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event handlers are specific types of functions that are invoked when the user interacts with the website. For instance, text can be shown when a button is clicked, or an image can appear when a mouse hovers over a text link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;arrays&#34;&gt;Arrays&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Array&#34;&gt;Arrays&lt;/a&gt; are one of the primary methods for storing data collections in JavaScript. An array is used to store ordered lists. Arrays can include all sorts of different data types, booleans, strings, numbers, objects, and even arrays within arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed array instantiation, and the associated properties (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Array/length&#34;&gt;.length&lt;/a&gt;) and methods (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Array/push&#34;&gt;.push&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Array/pop&#34;&gt;.pop&lt;/a&gt;) that come with arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;objects&#34;&gt;Objects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Object&#34;&gt;Objects&lt;/a&gt; are the other primary method for storing data collections in JavaScript. Rather than an ordered list of values like an array, objects are stored using key value pairs. These keys can be referenced using dot notation or bracket notation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then used both dot notation and bracket notation to access values that were stored within the objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;web-store-hackathon&#34;&gt;Web Store Hackathon&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hackathon was an individual 3 hour exercise in building a web store to compete with Amazon.com. We built upon our existing knowledge of HTML, CSS, and jQuery to create a basic layout for our e-commerce site. We then used objects to store our products that we would be selling, such as books and albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Remote Prep Week 2</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 09:42:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week completed already! With the end of week 2 brings the close to the first half of the class. At the end of each class, the instructors give a survey to determine if you feel &amp;lsquo;behind pace,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;on pace,&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;ahead of pace.&amp;rsquo; While I still feel I am in the &amp;lsquo;ahead of pace&amp;rsquo; category, I have been learning quite a bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction-to-javascript&#34;&gt;Introduction to JavaScript&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the cool things about Hack Reactor is that, no matter the complexity of the material, they always find a way to challenge you with the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of the week was very easy, covering terminal and operators in JavaScript. This gave me an opportunity to assist students newer to these concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;dom-manipulation&#34;&gt;DOM Manipulation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started learning about using JavaScript to manipulate the DOM. This was very interesting, as I have yet to really understand how to leverage JavaScript to manipulate the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conditionals&#34;&gt;Conditionals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This started with a brief refresher on the Boolean data type. We then spent most of our time working on If/Else statements. I really enjoyed taking what we had previously learned about DOM Manipulation and applying conditional statements based on user input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;while-loops&#34;&gt;While Loops&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very impressed with Hack Reactor as they took a seemingly simple concept and really made students push the limits of while loops. As I would normally use for loops for a majority of my functional programming, it was interesting to see how you can really leverage while loops, such as creating a simple rock, paper, scissors game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;jquery&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While jQuery can take a little getting used to, it definitely seems like the way to go for DOM Manipulation. I really enjoyed learning about jQuery effects as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;hackathon&#34;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a Halfway Hackathon! As a team, we were required to develop a project idea, and using all that we have learned so far, develop that idea individually in 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working with my group to problem solve and create a really fun version of the classic &amp;lsquo;Breakout&amp;rsquo; game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jz-breakout.divshot.io&#34;&gt;My version can be found here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Remote Prep Week 1</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 20:42:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fortunate enough to be in the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://hackreactor.com&#34;&gt;Hack Reactor&lt;/a&gt; Remote Prep class! The course is 4 weeks long, meeting 5 days a week for 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class time has flown by, and I have been able to work and get to know a majority of my classmates! I had wondered what it would be like to pair program remotely with people, and I honestly think it is just as good as if the person was sitting beside you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week was spent learning Markdown, HTML, and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first night was a &amp;lsquo;get to know the class&amp;rsquo; where each person &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/jrzimmerman/4bc55dd20ae8206689c0&#34;&gt;interviewed their paired partner&lt;/a&gt; and then had to introduce their partner to the class. We styled the information with Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;html&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second night focused on learning HTML and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jzimmerman.divshot.io/&#34;&gt;deploying our first site&lt;/a&gt;! This was a great experience. Since I knew some HTML already, the instructors hinted at using Bootstrap to style the site. I was also able to use the command line to deploy my website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://divshot.com/&#34;&gt;Divshot&lt;/a&gt;. One of the cool things about the Remote Prep class, is that the instructor and TAs are always willing to push you when you ask for extra material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;css&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third night was more difficult for me. I am probably the least exposed to CSS, and I was able to learn so much from the exercises. We also focused on importing media to websites such as YouTube videos, Google Maps, sound files, and external sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;forms&#34;&gt;Forms&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth night was all about styling multi-page web sites and learning how to use forms in HTML. We also discussed GET and POST, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7_LPdttKXPc&#34;&gt;how the internet works.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;css-frameworks&#34;&gt;CSS Frameworks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fifth day was all about advanced styling of layouts with CSS and an introduction to modern HTML and CSS frameworks! I am excited to be using &lt;a href=&#34;http://minimalcss.com/&#34;&gt;MinimalCSS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; from this point forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to continue posting what I have learned from class on a weekly basis! Happy learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-1/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Week 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-2/&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-3/&#34;&gt;Week 3&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href = &#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-remote-prep-week-4/&#34;&gt;Week 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Since My Last Hack Reactor Interview</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/since-my-last-hack-reactor-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 10:19:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/since-my-last-hack-reactor-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a multitude of things I have done since my last Hack Reactor interview to better prepare for the next interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have continued to study the beginning of Eloquent Javascript (especially rereading Chapter 5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed over my Wordpress blog to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;! This has allowed me to learn a lot of server side linux and briefly touch on &lt;a href=&#34;http://handlebarsjs.com/&#34;&gt;handlebars.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped my wife set up her own Ghost blog! She is starting her own online shop at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Store/Math-Snippets&#34;&gt;Teachers Pay Teachers&lt;/a&gt;. Check her out at &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathsnippets.com/&#34;&gt;Math Snippets&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up for a code school subscription. I found a deal for your first month at only 9 dollars. If you can try this out, I highly recommend the Javascript track! This holds especially true if you only have experience with Codecademy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed the optional &lt;a href=&#34;http://chatbuilder.hackreactor.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Chat Builder&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; project that used to be a requirement for Hack Reactor&amp;rsquo;s application process, this allowed me to gain valuable insight in jQuery and AJAX. &lt;a href=&#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/chatbuilder&#34;&gt;Check out my completed version!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have completed various &lt;a href=&#34;www.codewars.com/r/LQ0GHw&#34;&gt;Code Wars Koans&lt;/a&gt; in Javascript. I finally had an &amp;lsquo;ah-ha&amp;rsquo; moment when I started using map and reduce on koans rather than setting up a for loop, where applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to attempt to figure out the Google Maps and Places APIs. This has been really fun! Being a Geography major, I look forward to trying to wrap my head about location based services. I started off simply using a fixed location to show nearby restaurants, and I hope to get the geolocation to correctly work to show results any where in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this will solidify my background to finally break through. If you have been accepted into Hack Reactor, what have you done to push you over the edge?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>