<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hack Reactor on Justin Zimmerman</title>
    <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/categories/hack-reactor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hack Reactor on Justin Zimmerman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Justin Zimmerman.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 22:32:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://justinzimmerman.net/categories/hack-reactor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 12</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 22:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The realization that Week 12 has finally come to an end is definitely bitter-sweet. I have spent over 11 hours a day for the past 12 weeks learning Full-Stack Software Engineering. While I am looking forward getting back to a regular sleep schedule, I have learned more than I could imagine, and met many amazing people along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 12 consisted of finalizing resumes, creating cover letters, and preparing for the job search ahead. This was one of the most interesting weeks of Hack Reactor, although I can&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail on their job search process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have greatly enjoyed the Hack Reactor journey, and I hope if you are considering Hack Reactor that you have found my 12 weeks of blog posts insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 11</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 08:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With our product, Bestrida, to MVP (Minimum Viable Product) we will continue to improve our MVP features, as well as the look and feel of product, for the remainder of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our product finally received a much needed design overhaul, and we are definitely happy with the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/img/bestrida.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bestrida&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stretch-goals&#34;&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above image, we are able to pull from the Strava API segment effort data for the user to view additional metrics on how well they performed during their effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thesis-presentations&#34;&gt;Final Thesis Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to boil down three weeks of work into a simple 3 minute presentation, but fortunately I was paired with not only incredible developers, but excellent communicators. You can find our presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sw_mcAhgQo4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one more week until class is over! Onward to hiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 10</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 19:05:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-10/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With Thesis moving along very nicely, here is what happened in week 10!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;authentication&#34;&gt;Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges faced this week during thesis is removing API keys from the client side. With a mobile application, you should consider all of your code accessible for the world to see. This would allow for any user to view your API&amp;rsquo;s secret key allowing other user&amp;rsquo;s to make (potentially) malicious requests to the API. This should of course, be avoided at all costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reimplemented the authentication to be completely server side. To do this, we used passport.js and JSON Web Tokens. The client will send the JWT to the server on each request. Once sent, the server will then intercept the request, making sure the user has a valid token and that the token hasn&amp;rsquo;t expired yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a great learning experience for the entire team, and one that certainly helped us better understand token-based authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bestrida&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have finally made it to MVP! The server creates challenges, the user can view and accept these challenges, and we can finally declare a winner based off live Strava data. This has been a very challenging but rewarding process for the entire team, and we are so excited to show off our product to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With next week being a solo week for Christmas vacation, I will post again in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 9</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 08:13:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/hack-reactor-week-09/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Week 9 is finished at Hack Reactor, and thesis projects are in full swing! While there aren&amp;rsquo;t many things on the schedule, thesis is all about trying to build the best product in the 3 short weeks you have dedicated to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thesis&#34;&gt;Thesis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, this is a perfect summary of life during thesis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/wJ4IcDJ.gif&#34; alt=&#34;thesis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have no fear, little buddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While building a product can feel this way sometimes, I am having an awesome time learning and problem solving to create the best app we can possibly produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our thesis project, my group has decided to build upon Strava&amp;rsquo;s extensive API. We are seriously fortunate to have such a great API to leverage for our product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, here is a little bit about Bestrida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bestrida&#34;&gt;Bestrida&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name pays homage to Strava by also leaning upon it Swedish vocabulary. Strava is swedish for &amp;ldquo;to strive&amp;rdquo;, while Bestrida is swedish for &amp;ldquo;to challenge&amp;rdquo;. Which is exactly what our app does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bestrida will allow a user to challenge anyone they follow to a particular segment. The user will pick a person to challenge, a segment, and a date the challenge will be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of my friends are great to ride with, but like most cyclists, they are also always up for a short sprint through a well known Strava segment. This application will take your casual ride with friends to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for this week. Next week I will continue to describe Bestrida, and discuss topics learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Since My Last Hack Reactor Interview</title>
      <link>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/since-my-last-hack-reactor-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 10:19:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>justin.richard.zimmerman@gmail.com (Justin Zimmerman)</author>
      <guid>http://justinzimmerman.net/post/since-my-last-hack-reactor-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a multitude of things I have done since my last Hack Reactor interview to better prepare for the next interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have continued to study the beginning of Eloquent Javascript (especially rereading Chapter 5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed over my Wordpress blog to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;! This has allowed me to learn a lot of server side linux and briefly touch on &lt;a href=&#34;http://handlebarsjs.com/&#34;&gt;handlebars.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped my wife set up her own Ghost blog! She is starting her own online shop at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Store/Math-Snippets&#34;&gt;Teachers Pay Teachers&lt;/a&gt;. Check her out at &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathsnippets.com/&#34;&gt;Math Snippets&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up for a code school subscription. I found a deal for your first month at only 9 dollars. If you can try this out, I highly recommend the Javascript track! This holds especially true if you only have experience with Codecademy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed the optional &lt;a href=&#34;http://chatbuilder.hackreactor.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Chat Builder&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; project that used to be a requirement for Hack Reactor&amp;rsquo;s application process, this allowed me to gain valuable insight in jQuery and AJAX. &lt;a href=&#34;http://justinzimmerman.net/chatbuilder&#34;&gt;Check out my completed version!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have completed various &lt;a href=&#34;www.codewars.com/r/LQ0GHw&#34;&gt;Code Wars Koans&lt;/a&gt; in Javascript. I finally had an &amp;lsquo;ah-ha&amp;rsquo; moment when I started using map and reduce on koans rather than setting up a for loop, where applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to attempt to figure out the Google Maps and Places APIs. This has been really fun! Being a Geography major, I look forward to trying to wrap my head about location based services. I started off simply using a fixed location to show nearby restaurants, and I hope to get the geolocation to correctly work to show results any where in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this will solidify my background to finally break through. If you have been accepted into Hack Reactor, what have you done to push you over the edge?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>