<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hack Reactor on Justin Zimmerman</title>
    <link>https://jrzimmerman.github.io/categories/hack-reactor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hack Reactor on Justin Zimmerman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Justin Zimmerman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 22:32:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jrzimmerman.github.io/categories/hack-reactor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 12</title>
      <link>https://jrzimmerman.github.io/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 22:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrzimmerman.github.io/post/hack-reactor-week-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The realization that Week 12 has finally come to an end is definitely bitter-sweet. I have spent over 11 hours a day for the past 12 weeks learning Full-Stack Software Engineering. While I am looking forward getting back to a regular sleep schedule, I have learned more than I could imagine, and met many amazing people along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 12 consisted of finalizing resumes, creating cover letters, and preparing for the job search ahead. This was one of the most interesting weeks of Hack Reactor, although I can&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail on their job search process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have greatly enjoyed the Hack Reactor journey, and I hope if you are considering Hack Reactor that you have found my 12 weeks of blog posts insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Reactor Week 11</title>
      <link>https://jrzimmerman.github.io/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 08:54:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrzimmerman.github.io/post/hack-reactor-week-11/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With our product, Bestrida, to MVP (Minimum Viable Product) we will continue to improve our MVP features, as well as the look and feel of product, for the remainder of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our product finally received a much needed design overhaul, and we are definitely happy with the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jrzimmerman.github.io/img/bestrida.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bestrida&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stretch-goals&#34;&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above image, we are able to pull from the Strava API segment effort data for the user to view additional metrics on how well they performed during their effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thesis-presentations&#34;&gt;Final Thesis Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to boil down three weeks of work into a simple 3 minute presentation, but fortunately I was paired with not only incredible developers, but excellent communicators. You can find our presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sw_mcAhgQo4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one more week until class is over! Onward to hiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>